Guide to the Asian Americans at Stanford Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Asian Americans at Stanford collection
1969-2009
SC0972
Stanford University
1 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Collection pertains to Asian American students and staff at Stanford and includes publications, conference papers, student papers, clippings, articles, letters, and other materials. Items of note include the transcript of an interview with Mary L. Wong, 1976; student papers from a class on Asian American Identity, 1975 and undated; and the photograph album from the student residence Junipero House (with a few flyers and other paper items), 1971-72.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: Stanford student class papers may not be photocopied.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to Asian American students and staff at Stanford and includes publications, conference papers, student papers, clippings, articles, letters, and other materials. Items of note include the transcript of an interview with Mary L. Wong, 1976; student papers from a class on Asian American Identity, 1975 and undated; and the photograph album from the student residence Junipero House (with a few flyers and other paper items), 1971-72.
Access Terms
Wong, Mary L.; Asian Americans--California--Stanford
Collection Contents
- Original accession, 1973-1976; Accession ARCH-2009-265
  gift of Doug Chan
  - Interview with Mary L. Wong, Doug Chan and Mike Tim, interviewers [transcript], Feb. 26, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Koseki, Lawrence K., "Toward a Definition of Asian American Identity," conference paper, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poems by Alan Lau, George Leong, and Al Robles (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Secondary sources on Asian American issues (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Secondary sources on Asian American issues (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student papers from a class on Asian American Identity, 1975 and undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    NO PHOTOCOPIES ALLOWED
  - Testimony on the Employment Discrimination against the Chinese, presented at the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights Hearings, San Francisco, CA, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional material, 1969-1970; Accession ARCH-2009-266
  gift of Nelson Nagai
  - Asian American Student Alliance Newsletter, clippings, informational letters, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additional material, 1984; Accession ARCH-2009-267
  gift of Eric Mark
  - The 1983-84 Stanford Asian American Sourcebook [date book style, annotated], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional material, 1971-1972; Accession ARCH-2009-268
  gift of Harumi Befu
  - Photograph Album from Junipero House (with a few flyers and other paper items), 1971-72 (Box 2)
- Additional material, 1973-2009; Accession ARCH-2009-269
  transferred from Okada House
  - Articles (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Asian American Source Book (Stanford publication), 1975, ca. 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Asian American Women, a journal published at Stanford University, May 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Doug Chan, letters, bibliography, newspaper article and other items, 1974-75 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kwonping Ho, statement on Shockley, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous letters, notes, 1974-75 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Origins Panel program (1 copy autographed) and audio disc, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Proposals for a new name for Junipero, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - SAPAAC miscellany, 1989-95 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - SAPAAC News, The newsletter of the Stanford Asian/Pacific American Alumni/ae Club, 1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)